CHRISTIAN SIKU

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER E-mail | Github| LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I'm a transversal profile with 1 year of experience in the management of web development and embedded electronics projects. Sociable and determined, I pursue innovation across the world and its cultures. Organize, renew and learn are my watchwords. Something I can't do? I will learn it.

SKILLS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, Jest

Back-End: Ruby, Ruby On Rails, SQL, NoSQL, PHP, MySQL, and Rspec

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving,

Organization Skills, Time Management, Work Ethic, Attention to detail, Adaptability, Prioritizing

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full-Stack Web Developer

February, 2022 - May, 2022

Portfolio Project — This project was a portfolio that helps me get known in the development world.

- Built with: (JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3).
- Live demo

Crypto Tracker App — Crypto-Tracker is a web application for cryptocurrencies that provides some information about the current rank, price, volume, ... of the top 100 most used cryptocurrencies in the world. Built with: (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 and API REST).

• <u>Live demo</u>

Space-X Traveller Hub e — This project was based on an online website for a conference.

- Built with: (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3).
- Live demo

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) May, 2022-Present

- Mentored junior software developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE (Remote)

March, 2022-Present

Remote FullStack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

KIGALI INDEPENDENT UNIVERSITY (Gisenyi, Western province, Rwanda)

September, 2018 - December, 2021

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

- Thesis: Intelligent road Traffic control system.
- Awards and honors: First Class Honor.